Guide to the John Franklin Enders Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1930-1972; Series II; 5.25' (13 boxes)
  - Articles and Papers
    - 1954
      - Mumps (revised chapter in Diagnostic Procedures for Virus and Rickettsial Diseases ) (Box 93, Folder 89)
      - The Present Status of Tissue Culture Techniques in the Study of the Poliomyelitis Viruses (Box 93, Folder 90)
      - The Propagation in Tissue Cultures of Cytopathogenic Agents from Patients with Measles (Box 93, Folder 91)
      - Tissue Cultures in the Study of Immunity Retrospection and Anticipation (Box 93, Folder 92)
    - 1955
      - Dyer Lecture (Box 93, Folder 93)
      - Observations on Certain Viruses Causing Exanthematous Disease in Man (Box 93, Folder 94)
      - Observations on Certain Viruses Causing Exanthematous Disease in Man: correspondence (Box 93, Folder 95)
      - Random Remarks on Certain Viruses and their Behavior (Box 93, Folder 96)
      - Remarks on the Present Status of Knowledge Concerning the Poliomyelitis Viruses (Box 93, Folder 97)
    - 1956
      - Association of Coxsackie B Virus and Mycarditis in Infants (Box 94, Folder 98)
      - Behavior of Monkeys After Inoculation of Virus Derived from Patients with Measles and Propagated in Tissue Culture Together with Observations on Spontaneous Infections of These Animals by an Agent Exhibiting Similar Antigenic Properties (Box 94, Folder 99)
      - The Future of Virus Studies in Tissue Culture (Box 94, Folder 100)
      - Measles Virus: A Summary of Experiments Concerned with Isolation, Properties and Behavior (Box 94, Folder 101)
      - Poliomyelitis (Box 94, Folder 102)
      - The Present Status of Etiologic Discovery in Viral Diseases (Box 94, Folder 103)
    - 1957
      - Cerebral Palsy (Box 94, Folder 104)
      - Clinical Associations of Enteric Viruses with Particular Reference to Agents Exhibiting Properties of the ECHO Group (Box 94, Folder 105)
      - Comments on Viral Cytopathogenicity (Box 94, Folder 106)
      - Cultivation of Measles Virus in Human Amnion Cells and in the Developing Chick Embryo (Box 94, Folder 107)
      - The Significance of Tissue Culture in Modern Virus Research (Box 94, Folder 108)
    - 1958
      - Address to the Graduating Class of the Medical School at Western Reserve University (Box 94, Folder 109)
      - Comments on the Contribution of Viruses to Biology (Box 94, Folder 110)
      - Comments on the Contribution of Viruses to Biology: correspondence (Box 94, Folder 111)
      - An Evaluation of Various Tissues in Culture for Isolation of Eastern Equine Encephalitis Virus (Box 94, Folder 112)
      - Experiences with a Live Attenuated Measles Virus (Box 94, Folder 113)
      - Hypersensitivity to Viral Infections (Box 94, Folder 114)
      - An Inhibitor of Viral Activity Appearing in Infected Cell Cultures (Box 94, Folder 115)
      - Mumps (chapter in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man, 3rd ed.) (Box 94, Folder 116)
      - Notes on the Susceptibility and Resistance of Animal Cells to Mammalian Viruses (Box 95, Folder 117)
      - Propagation of Measles Virus in Cultures of Chick Embryo Cells (Box 95, Folder 118)
      - Recent Advances in Knowledge of the Measles Virus (Box 95, Folder 119)
      - Some Recent Advances in Varicella and Measles (Box 95, Folder 120)
      - Tissue Culture Technics Employed in the Propagation of Viruses and Rickettsiae (chapter in Viral and Rickettsial Diseases of Man, 3rd ed.) (Box 95, Folder 121)
      - The Virology of Giant Cell Pneumonia (Box 95, Folder 122)
    - 1959
      - Disease in Macacus Monkeys Inoculated with ECHO Viruses (Box 95, Folder 123)
      - Further Studies on an Inhibitor of Viral Activity Appearing in Infected Cell Cultures and Its Role in Chronic Viral Infections (Box 95, Folder 124)
      - Immunization of Children with a Live Attenuated Measles Virus (Box 95, Folder 125)
      - Isolation of Measles Virus at Autopsy from Cases of Giant Cell Pneumonia Without Rash (Box 95, Folder 126)
      - Persistence of Measles Virus and Depression of Antibody Formation in Patients with Giant Cell Pneumonia Following Measles (Box 95, Folder 127)
      - Studies on the Virus of Measles (Box 95, Folder 128)
      - Tissue Culture: Illustrations of Its Application to Problems of Human Viral Disease (Box 95, Folder 129)
    - 1960
      - Attenuated Measles Virus as Vaccine: Experimental Background (Box 95, Folder 130)
      - Book review of Mirage of Health (Box 95, Folder 131)
      - A Consideration of the Mechanisms of Resistance to Viral Infection Based on Recent Studies of the Agents of Measles and Poliomyelitis (Box 95, Folder 132)
      - The Effect of Trypsin on Representative Myxoviruses (Box 96, Folder 133)
      - Studies on an Attenuated Measles Virus Vaccine: I-IV (Box 96, Folder 134)
      - Studies on an Attenuated Measles Virus Vaccine: V-VIII (Box 96, Folder 135)
      - Survival of Poliovirus at Elevated Temperatures (60-75C) (Box 96, Folder 136)
    - 1961
      - Alteration of Cellular Resistance to Sindbis Virus in Mixed Cultures of Human Cells Attributable to Interferon (Box 96, Folder 137)
      - A Critique of the Plaque Assay Technique in Bottle Cultures (Box 96, Folder 138)
      - Cytopathogenicity of Mumps Virus in Cultures of Chick Embryo and Human Amnion Cells (Box 96, Folder 139)
      - Development of Attenuated Measles Virus Vaccines: A Summary of Recent Investigation (Box 96, Folder 140)
      - Development and Evaluation of an Attenuated Measles Virus Vaccine (Box 96, Folder 141)
      - The Effect of Ammonium Sulfate Fractions of Horse Serum on Ribonuclease Activity (Box 96, Folder 142)
      - The Effect of Trypsin on Representative Myxoviruses (Box 96, Folder 143)
      - An Interferon Appearing in Cell Cultures Infected with Measles Virus (Box 96, Folder 144)
      - An Interferon Appearing in Cell Cultures Infected with Measles Virus (Box 96, Folder 145)
      - Markers for Edmonston Measles Virus (Box 96, Folder 146)
      - Measles Virus: Historical Review, Isolation and Behavior in Various Systems (Box 96, Folder 147)
      - A Note on the Presence of Inclusion Bodies in Dividing Human Kidney Cells Infected with Group Associated Virus (Box 96, Folder 148)
      - A Summary of Three Years' Experience Utilizing Edmonston Attenuated Measles Strain (Box 96, Folder 149)
      - Vaccination Against Measles (Box 96, Folder 150)
    - 1962
      - Alteration of Cellular Resistance to Sindbis Virus in Mixed Cultures of Human Cells Attributable to Interferon (Box 97, Folder 151)
      - Attenuated Measles Vaccine in Children with Acute Leukemia (Box 97, Folder 152)
      - Chromosomal Disturbances Observed in Human Fetal Renal Cells Transformed in vitro by Simian Virus 40 and Carried in Culture (Box 97, Folder 153)
      - Comments on Some Prospective Problems in Animal Virology (Box 97, Folder 154)
      - Development of Attenuated Measles-Virus Vaccines: A Summary of Recent Investigation (Box 97, Folder 155)
      - Growth of Poliovirus in Cotton-plugged Monkey Kidney Cell Cultures (Box 97, Folder 156)
      - Inhibition of Arbor Viruses (Group A) by a Protein-Like Constituent of a Corynebacterium (Box 97, Folder 157)
      - Markers for Edmonston Measles Virus (Box 97, Folder 158)
      - Measles Virus: Historical Review, Isolation, and Behavior in Various Systems (Box 97, Folder 159)
      - Reactions of Children with Acute Leukemia to Vaccination with Attenuated Measles Virus Vaccine (Box 97, Folder 160)
      - Recent Observations on Reactions of Cells in Culture to Viral Infection (Box 97, Folder 161)
      - A Simple Rapid Method for Production of Viral Antibody in Mice (Box 97, Folder 162)
      - Transformation Induced by Simian Virus 40 in Newborn Syrian Hamster Renal Cell Cultures (Box 97, Folder 163)
      - Use of Edmonston Attenuated Measles Strain: A Summary of Three Years' Experience (Box 97, Folder 164)
    - 1963
      - Chromosomal Disturbances Observed in Human Fetal Renal Cells Transformed in vitro by Simian Virus 40 and Carried in Culture (Box 97, Folder 165)
      - "Cyclopin": A Trypsin Sensitive Constituent of Penicillium cyclopium with Antiviral Properties (Introduction) (Box 97, Folder 166)
      - Further Studies on SV40-Induced Transformation in Human Renal Cell Cultures: I. Eventual Failure of Subcultivation Despite a Continuing High Rate of Cell Division (Box 97, Folder 167)
      - Further Studies on SV40-Induced Transformation in Human Renal Cell Cultures: II. Effects of Anti-Viral Serum and Interferon on the Progression of Transformation (Box 97, Folder 168)
      - Hypersensitivity to Viral Infections (Box 97, Folder 169)
      - Isolation of Measles Virus from the Washed Leucocytic Fraction of Blood (Box 97, Folder 170)
      - Measles Vaccination (Box 97, Folder 171)
      - Mumps (Chapter 33 in Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man, 3rd ed.) (Box 97, Folder 172)
      - Oncogenic Viruses (Box 97, Folder 173)
      - Personal Recollections of Dr. Hugh Ward (Box 97, Folder 174)
      - Some Prospective Problems in Animal Virology (Box 97, Folder 175)
      - Transformation Induced by Simian Virus 40 in Human Renal Cell Cultures (Box 97, Folder 176)
      - Vaccination Against Measles (Box 97, Folder 177)
    - 1964
      - Alteration in Cell Antigens Induced by Viruses (Box 97, Folder 178)
      - Cell Transformation by Viruses as Illustrated by the Response of Human and Hamster Renal Cells (Box 98, Folder 179)
      - Cell Transformation by Viruses as Illustrated by the Response of Human and Hamster Renal Cells to Simian Virus 40 (Box 98, Folder 180)
      - Forward to proceedings of the Séminaire du Centre International de l'Enfance (Box 98, Folder 181)
      - Francis Home and His Experimental Approach to Medicine (Box 98, Folder 182)
      - Further Studies on SV40-Induced Transformation in Human Renal Cell Cultures: I. Eventual Failure of Subcultivation Despite a Continuing High Rate of Cell Division (Box 98, Folder 183)
      - Investigations on Infectious Hepatitis (Box 98, Folder 184)
      - Laboratory Diagnosis of Measles Infection (chapter in Diagnostic Procedures for Virus and Rickettsial Diseases ) (Box 98, Folder 185)
      - Measles (Chapter 36 in Viral and Rickettsial Infections in Man ) (Box 98, Folder 186)
      - Measles in Children with Malignancy Problems and Prevention (Box 98, Folder 187)
      - Persistent Polioviral Infection of Intact Human Amniotic Membrane Without Apparent Cytopathic Effect (Box 98, Folder 188)
      - Recovery of an Interferon-Like Substance from Cerebrospinal Fluid (Box 98, Folder 189)
      - Remarks on Oncogenic Virus-Cell Relationships (Box 98, Folder 190)
      - Specific Complement Fixing Tumor Antigens in Human Cells Morphologically Transformed by SV40 Virus (Box 98, Folder 191)
      - Studies on Viral Inhibitors of Biological Origin: I. Inhibition of Viral Replication by Protein-Like Constituents of Bacteria (Box 98, Folder 192)
      - Thoughts on Future Contributions of Virology to Medicine (Box 98, Folder 193)
      - Transformation Induced by Simian Virus 40 in Human Renal Cell Cultures: I. Morphology and Growth Characteristics (Box 98, Folder 194)
      - Viral Inhibitors of Biological Origin: II. A Viral Inhibitory Factor Obtained from E. coli 0111 and Inhibition of Viral Replication by Nucleic Acid Derivatives (Box 99, Folder 195)
      - A Virus Inhibitor in Pharyngeal Washings from Patients with Influenza (Box 99, Folder 196)
    - 1965
      - Cell Transformation by Viruses as Illustrated by the Response of Human and Hamster Renal Cells to Simian Virus 40 (Box 99, Folder 197)
      - Clinical and Immune Response of Alien Hosts to Inoculation with Measles, Rinderpest, and Canine Distemper Viruses (Box 99, Folder 198)
      - A Consideration of the Role of Oncogenic Viruses in the Development of Malignant Changes in vitro Based on Experiments with Simian Virus 40 (Box 99, Folder 199)
      - Extensive Polynucleate Giant Cell Formation After X-Irradiation or Addition of Colchicine in SV40 Transformed Syrian Hamster Cells (Box 99, Folder 200)
      - Growth and Cytopathic Effect of Rubella Virus in a Line of Green Monkey Kidney Cells (Box 99, Folder 201)
      - Inhibition of Arboviruses by a Constituent of Staphylococcus (Box 99, Folder 202)
      - Measles Virus (Chapter 18 of Diagnostic Procedures for Viral and Rickettsial Diseases, 3rd ed.) (Box 99, Folder 203)
      - Mumps Virus (Chapter 32 of Viral and Rickettsial Infections of Man ) (Box 99, Folder 204)
      - Persistent Polioviral Infection of Intact Human Amniotic Membrane Without Apparent Cytopathic Effect (Box 99, Folder 205)
      - Remarks at the Official Opening Session of the Fifth Interscience Conference on Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy of the Fourth International Congress of Chemotherapy (Box 99, Folder 206)
      - Studies on Transformation of Syrian Hamster Cells by Simian Virus 40: I. Acquisition of Oncogenicity by Virus-exposed Cells Apparently Unassociated with the Viral Genome (Box 99, Folder 207)
    - 1966
      - Comparison of the Cytomorphology of in vitro SV40 Transformed Hamster Embryo Cells with the Histopathology of the Neoplasms Which They Induce in the Homologous Host (Box 99, Folder 208)
      - Early Effects of SV40 on Growth in vitro of Hamster and Human Tissue Cells (Box 99, Folder 209)
      - Increased Resistance to Herpes Simplex Virus of Hamster and Human Cells Transformed by SV40 (Box 99, Folder 210)
      - Infectious Diseases Society of America (Box 99, Folder 211)
      - Present Status of Live Rubeola Vaccines (Box 99, Folder 212)
      - Presentation of Work on Oncogenicity of SV40 (Box 99, Folder 213)
      - The Pursuit of a Disappearing Virus (Box 99, Folder 214)
    - 1967
      - Comments on Present Directions of Virus Research (Box 99, Folder 215)
      - Development of S and T Antigens and Oncogenicity in Hamster Embryonic Cell Lines Exposed to SV40 (Box 99, Folder 216)
      - Infectious Diseases and the Children's Medical Center in the Next Decade (Box 99, Folder 217)
      - An Informal Account of the Origin and Work of the Research Division of Infectious Diseases, Children's Hospital Medical Center 1947-1967 (Box 99, Folder 218)
      - Poliovirus Replication and Cytopathogenicity in Monolayer Hamster Cell Cultures Fused with Beta Propiolactone-Inactivated Sendai Virus (Box 99, Folder 219)
      - Remarks on Future Developments in Medical Virology (Box 99, Folder 220)
      - Replication of Poliovirus I in Chick Embryo and Hamster Cells Exposed to Sendai Virus (Box 99, Folder 221)
    - 1968
      - Development of S and T Antigens and Oncogenicity in Hamster Embryonic Cell Lines Exposed to SV40 (Box 99, Folder 222)
      - Does EB Virus Cause Infectious Mononucleosis? (Box 99, Folder 223)
      - Further Observations on Replication of Type I Poliovirus in Naturally Resistant Fused Cell Cultures (Box 99, Folder 224)
      - Lack of Relationship Between Virus-Specific Surface and Transplantation Antigens in Hamster Cells Transformed by Simian Papovavirus SV40 (Box 99, Folder 225)
      - Poliovirus Replication and Cytopathogenicity in Monolayer Hamster Cell Cultures Fused with Beta Propiolactone-Inactivated Sendai Virus (Box 99, Folder 226)
      - Vaccinia Virus Replication and Cytopathic Effect Cultures of Phytohemagglutinin-Treated Human Peripheral Blood Leukocytes (Box 100, Folder 227)
      - Virus and Cancer: Problems of Relationship of Virus to the Transformed Cell and to Cancerigenesis as Illustrated by Experiments with the Oncogenic Agent Simian Virus 40 (Box 100, Folder 228)
    - 1969
      - Establishment of Human Fetal Gut Cultures and their Utilization for the Growth of Human Viruses (Box 100, Folder 229)
      - Establishment of Lines from Normal Human Blood Leukocytes by Co-Cultivation with a Leukocyte Line Derived from a Leukemic Child (Box 100, Folder 230)
      - Feline Herpesvirus Infection in Fused Cultures of Naturally Resistant Human Cells (Box 100, Folder 231)
      - Remarks on the Role of Viruses in Human Disease (Box 100, Folder 232)
      - A Study of Variation and Progression in Oncogenicity in an SV40-Transformed Hamster Heart Cell Line and its Clones (Box 100, Folder 233)
    - 1970
      - Cultures of Segments of Human Fetal Intestine: Applications to Cytologic and Virologic Investigations (Box 100, Folder 234)
      - Rubella Vaccination (Box 100, Folder 235)
      - Trypsinized Placental Cell Cultures for the Propagation of Viruses and as "Feeder Layers" (Box 100, Folder 236)
      - Viruses in Hiding (Box 100, Folder 237)
    - 1971
      - Forward and Introductory Remarks from the International Children's Centre Seminar on Viral Hepatitis (Box 100, Folder 238)
    - 1972
      - Early Observations on Cytopathogenicity of Poliovirus (Box 100, Folder 239)
      - Isolation of AGMK Cells Partially Resistant to SV40: Identification of the Resistant Step (Box 100, Folder 240)
    - Undated
      - The Laboratory Diagnosis on Certain Viral Encephalitides (Box 100, Folder 241)
      - A Note on the Relationship of Complement Fixation and Anaphylaxis (Box 100, Folder 242)
      - Recent Advances in Certain Fields of Tuberculosis Research (Box 100, Folder 243)
  - Lecture and presentation notes
    - Harvard Medical School lectures
      - Bacteriology and immunology, pp.1-54, 1943-1945 (Box 100, Folder 244)
      - Bacteriology and immunology, pp. 55-109, 1943-1945 (Box 100, Folder 245)
      - The Spirochacte, 1934, 1937-1941 (Box 100, Folder 246)
      - The Spirochacte, undated (Box 100, Folder 247)
      - Various topics, 1944-1958 (Box 101, Folder 248-249)
      - Various topics, 1960, 1963, 1967, [196?] (Box 101, Folder 250)
      - Various topics, undated (Box 101, Folder 251)
    - Club and society presentations, 1953, 1962, 1964 (Box 101, Folder 252)
    - Miscellaneous hospital and laboratory staff presentations, 1947-1948, 1961 (Box 101, Folder 253)
    - Talk on laboratory diagnosis of mumps infections before the Massachusetts Public Health Association, 1947 (Box 101, Folder 254)
    - Talk on mumps before the staffs of Hartford Hospital and Massachusetts Memorial Hospital, 1949 (Box 101, Folder 255)
    - Unidentified presentations, 1969, undated (Box 101, Folder 256)
- Laboratory Notebooks, 1947-1976; Series III; 14' (34 Boxes)
  The material in this series is arranged alphabetically following the index to experiments. Notebooks with topical titles are followed by those titled by personal name.
  - Index to experiments, 1949-1952 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Complement Fixation Tests, 1947-1951 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Influenza (Interferon) Studies, undated (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Jimmy Fund, undated (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Measles: Volume I, Circa 1954-1956 (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Measles: Volume II, Circa 1955-1958 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Measles: Volume III, Circa 1958-1961 (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Measles: Volume IV, Circa 1961-1967, 1970 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Polio Stool Data, Circa 1952 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Polyoma: Volume I, Circa 1959-1961 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Polyoma: Volume II, Circa 1961-1963 (Box 104, Folder 11)
  - Ackinson: Volume I, Circa 1963 (Box 104, Folder 12)
  - Arnold, John H.: Volume I, Circa 1955-1957 (Box 104, Folder 13)
  - August, Charles: Volume I, Circa 1966-1967 (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - Berg, Robert B., circa 1958-1959, circa 1960 (Box 105, Folder 15-16)
  - Berson, Eliot: Volume I, Circa 1960 (Box 105, Folder 17)
  - Campillo-Sainz, Carlos: Volume I, Circa 1952-1953 (Box 106, Folder 18)
  - Carver, David H.: Volume I, Circa 1961 (Box 106, Folder 19)
  - Carver, David H.: Volume II, Circa 1961-1962 (Box 106, Folder 20)
  - Carver, David H.: Volume III, Circa 1962-1963 (Box 106, Folder 21)
  - Carver, David H.: Volume IV, Circa 1963 (Box 107, Folder 22)
  - Chally, Cecil: Volume I, Circa 1964 (Box 107, Folder 23)
  - De Maeyer, Edward: Volume I, Circa 1958-1959 (Box 107, Folder 24)
  - De Maeyer, Edward: Volume II, Circa 1959-1960 (Box 107, Folder 25)
  - De Maeyer, Edward: Volume III, Circa 1960 (Box 108, Folder 26)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Notes and References Volume I, undated (Box 108, Folder 27)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume I, Circa 1961-1962 (Box 108, Folder 28)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume II, Circa 1962 (Box 108, Folder 29)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume III, Circa 1962-1963 (Box 109, Folder 30)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume IV, Circa 1962-1963 (Box 109, Folder 31)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume V, Circa 1963 (Box 109, Folder 32)
  - Dull, H. Bruce: Volume VI, Circa 1963-1964 (Box 109, Folder 33)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume II, Circa 1951-1953 (Box 110, Folder 34)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume III, Circa 1953-1954 (Box 110, Folder 35)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume IV, Circa 1954-1956 (Box 110, Folder 36)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume V, Circa 1956-1958 (Box 110, Folder 37)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume VI, Circa 1958-1959 (Box 111, Folder 38)
  - Enders, John F.: Volume VII, Circa 1960-1965 (Box 111, Folder 39)
  - Enders, John F.: SV40: Volume I, Circa 1963-1964 (Box 111, Folder 40)
  - Enders, John F.: SV40: Volume II, Circa 1965-1966 (Box 111, Folder 41)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume I, Circa 1964 (Box 112, Folder 42)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume II, Circa 1965-1967 (Box 112, Folder 43)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume III, Circa 1966-1967 (Box 112, Folder 44)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume IV, Circa 1967-1969 (Box 112, Folder 45)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume V, Circa 1969-1970 (Box 113, Folder 46)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume VII, Circa 1971-1972 (Box 113, Folder 47)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume VIII, Circa 1972-1974 (Box 113, Folder 48)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume IX, Circa 1973-1975 (Box 114, Folder 49)
  - Enders, John F. and Grogan, Elizabeth A.: Volume X, Circa 1975-1976 (Box 114, Folder 50)
  - Frothingham, Thomas E.: Volume I, Circa 1957-1958 (Box 114, Folder 51)
  - Frothingham, Thomas E.: Volume II, Circa 1958 March-December (Box 115, Folder 52)
  - Gajdusek, D. Carleton: Complement Fixation Data, Circa 1949-1951 (Box 115, Folder 53)
  - Gajdusek, D. Carleton: Polio Data, Circa 1951 (Box 115, Folder 54)
  - Gajdusek, D. Carleton: Animal Sera Index Volume I, Circa 1949-1950 (Box 115, Folder 55)
  - Grenier, B., Circa 1956 (Box 116, Folder 56)
  - Gresser, Ion: Volume I, undated (Box 116, Folder 57)
  - Gresser, Ion: Volume II, Circa 1959-1961 (Box 116, Folder 58)
  - Gresser, Ion: Volume III, Circa 1959-1961 (Box 116, Folder 59)
  - Gresser, Ion: Volume IV, undated (Box 117, Folder 60)
  - Gresser, Ion: Volume V, Circa 1961 (Box 117, Folder 61)
  - Gresser, Ion: Influenza-Infectious Mono, undated (Box 117, Folder 62)
  - Gresser, Ion, [1963?] (Box 117, Folder 63)
  - Gresser, Ion, [1964?], circa 1962-1963 (Box 118, Folder 64-65)
  - Gresser, Ion; Gunalp: Warts, hybridization, induction, X-rays, Circa 1963-1964 (Box 118, Folder 66)
  - Gresser, Ion; Grogan, Elizabeth A., Circa 1964-1965 (Box 118, Folder 67)
  - Gresser, Ion; Naficy, Kiarash: Fungi, Circa 1963 (Box 119, Folder 68)
  - Griffith, John F.: Volume I, Circa 1967-1968 (Box 119, Folder 69)
  - Griffith, John F.: Volume II, Circa 1968-1969 (Box 119, Folder 70)
  - Grogan, Elizabeth A.
    See: box 112, folders 42-45 See: box 113, folders 46-50 See: box 118, folder 67
  - Gunalp
    See: box 118, folder 66
  - Ho, M.: Volume I, Circa 1957-1958 (Box 119, Folder 71)
  - Irvine, Alexander R.: Volume I, Circa 1962 (Box 120, Folder 72)
  - Kahn, Henry S.: Volume I, Circa 1968 (Box 120, Folder 73)
  - Lang, David J.: Volume I, Circa 1963-1965 (Box 120, Folder 74)
  - Lang, David J.: Volume II, Circa 1964-1965 (Box 120, Folder 75)
  - Lang, David J.: Volume III, Circa 1964-1965 (Box 121, Folder 76)